openathens.net 2017-06-06

# Privacy & Cookies - OpenAthens

This Privacy and Cookie Policy explains how Eduserv (including OpenAthens) uses personal information we collect, why we collect it, how we safeguard it, and how you can control that data. We are absolutely committed to protecting the privacy of people who use our products and services, or who visit our website.

**What information do we gather?**

Essentially we collect two types of information:

– Information that relates to and can identify you (eg. name, address, organisation)  
– Anonymous information that doesn’t identify you personally, for example about your computer and about your use of this website.

**How we collect your information**

We may collect personal information from you when you:

– Sign up to an event or newsletter.  
– Purchase any of our services.  
– Become a user, administrator or editor of our Identity & Access and Licence Negotiation services.  
– Become a user of compute.cloud.eduserv.org.uk or dashboard.cloud.eduserv.org.uk

Whenever we collect information about you personally, it is only done with your knowledge and consent and you have the right to ask us to stop using this information, for example by unsubscribing to an email newsletter by following a link.

If we collect any personal information (eg. through a form) we will be clear about it and draw your attention to our Privacy and Cookies Policy.

We collect anonymous information from visitors to our website using analytics tools, cookies and web logs.

**Our use of cookies**

We want to make our online services as user-friendly and relevant as possible. To do this, we sometimes place small amounts of information on your device (eg. your computer or mobile phone), including small files known as cookies, to help us understand how you use our web services.

These files cannot identity you personally, but can be used by us to, for example:

– Deliver a service that recognises your device so you don’t have to give the same information twice.  
– Personalise and improve your user experience.  
– Measure how many people are using our services, the relevance of our web content and other performance-related data

Examples of cookies set by Eduserv:

Google Analytics: This is a web analytics tool provided by Google that enables us to evaluate how users (anonymously) use our site, which of our communications campaigns are working and which parts of the site need improvement. You can use the Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-on to disable tracking by Google Analytics.

Google DoubleClick: Although we do not feature advertising on our site we have implemented Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting in Google Analytics based on Display Advertising. This enables us to develop the site and content around our users’ interests using anonymous data. You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the Ads Settings.

Identity_Session: Set by the web content management system to remember certain settings, such as which part of the site you were using. This session cookie is destroyed each time you close your browser.

WordPress: Our blog runs on the WordPress CMS and cookies are used to store basic data on your interactions with WordPress (for example commenting, sharing) and whether you have logged into WordPress. We use a session cookie to remember your log-in for you if you are a registered user and we deem these as being strictly necessary to the working of the website.

In accordance with the latest guidance we have adopted an ‘implied consent’ policy. If you are not happy for cookies to be set on your device you can:

– Discontinue use of the site.  
– Delete the cookies following your visit.  
– Browse the site using your browser’s anonymous usage setting (Incognito in Chrome, InPrivate for Internet Explorer, Private Browsing in Firefox, Safari, etc)

You can find out more about cookies and how to manage them at www.allaboutcookies.org

**How we use your information**

Personal data

If you have subscribed to any of our services we will use the information you have provided us to keep you updated unless you tell us otherwise.

We may also contact you with information about our products and services that we think you may be interested in.

We will also use your personal details if you have indicated that you wish to be informed of news, events and services either when attending an event, or signing up to a newsletter. You can choose to unsubscribe at any time. If there is no unsubscribe button in an email it is usually because it’s part of a service communication to customers.

We need personal data in order to confirm a user’s entitlement to parts of our Identity & Access Management services.

We may need to provide service providers and suppliers that your organisation subscribes to with access to some data about you so that they can confirm your entitlements and grant access to software and data.

Anonymous information

Anonymous information about the way people use our website can be aggregated into statistics that show us how our websites are used and help us improve the user experience of the services we provide.

We use Google Analytics to collect information about use of our website. It helps us to understand how often users visit, what pages they view, their geographic location and so on. Google Analytics does not use personally identifiable information but instead allows us to see patterns and assess the effectiveness of our content. We can also place anonymous information into audience segments based on location and interests and serve relevant content that we think will be of interest to you.

Anonymous data may also be essential to the security of the services we offer or a necessary part of a service – for example, for certain Identity & Access Management customers.

**How we protect your information**

Eduserv maintains appropriate technical and operational measures to safeguard your personal data. The servers containing your personal data are located in secure data centre locations where access is limited to authorised staff. All data transmissions to and from Eduserv (e.g. from the OpenAthens database) are encrypted. Any password you submit to Eduserv is one-way encrypted before it is stored. Personal data is processed automatically by Eduserv’s systems without human intervention as far as possible.

The personal data which Eduserv holds is never modified or disclosed to any third party other than as described in this policy. We never sell, rent or trade your personal data. Service Providers in the EU and USA are obliged to follow regulations similar to the Data Protection Act. If we engage Service Providers from elsewhere we receive equivalent undertakings so that your personal data remains protected.

We will remove your personal data from our live systems as soon as you or the administrator for your organisation instructs us to do so. Once removed from our OpenAthens service, personal data is retained for up to twelve months but only as part of our backup procedures.

We continually monitor our systems and practices to verify that this policy is followed to ensure the security and confidentiality of the information that we collect. All our staff have been instructed in the importance of the Data Protection Act, information security and this privacy policy.

**Access to your information**

You have the right to ask us:

– to give you a description of the personal data that we hold for you  
– to tell you why we are holding it  
– to tell you who it could be disclosed to  
– to let you have a copy of your personal data  
– to require us to correct any mistakes  
– to remove you from any of our mailing lists

Please use the contact details below if you want to make use of these rights.

If your our organisation operates any OpenAthens service, the organisation that issued your OpenAthens account is the data controller for your personal data – even if that information is passed to Eduserv as part of the service. So if you wish to find out about the information that is held about you, or amend it, you should contact your organisation’s OpenAthens administrator in the first instance.

MyAthens users can also view their personal data by logging on to their own MyAthens account.

If your organisation operates an OpenAthens-enabled local authentication service (such as Shibboleth or OpenAthens LA), user accounts are not created, so no personal data is passed to Eduserv.

**More information about this policy**

Eduserv, a company limited by guarantee (registered in England and Wales, company number 3763109), and a charity (charity number 1079456), whose registered office is at Royal Mead, Railway Place, Bath BA1 1SR is the data controller for the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998 for information collected through this website.

As a condition of the use of our services, you consent to the terms of this privacy policy. We may update this policy from time to time. The latest version will be available on our website and we’ll publish a prominent notice whenever something changes.

This privacy policy applies only to the use of your personal data by Eduserv. The use of personal data by your organisation or any service provider or supplier will be governed by their own privacy policies. Eduserv is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of any third party websites linked to from Eduserv websites.

**Contact us**

If you would like to contact us about any aspect of our Privacy Policy, please email contact@eduserv.org.uk or write to us at the postal address above.

November 2014
